<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technical on Ben Ewing | Improper Prior</title>
    <link>/categories/technical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technical on Ben Ewing | Improper Prior</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/technical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning SQL</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/23/learning-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/23/learning-sql/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been using the past few weeks to improve my SQL fluency, and I just wanted to share a few quick resources that I’ve found useful.
SQLZoo. The quizzes and questions hit the perfect balance of challenging but not so hard that it breaks my sense of flow.
The sqlite3 package for Python and RSQLite package for R. While one certainly could install and use something like PostgreSQL on their laptop (and it’s definitely a useful tool to learn!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Principal Component Analysis to Estimate Socioeconomic Status</title>
      <link>/post/2020/03/21/using-principal-component-analysis-to-estimate-socioeconomic-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/03/21/using-principal-component-analysis-to-estimate-socioeconomic-status/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionPrincipal Component Analysis (PCA) is a dimension reduction technique that is commonly used in the social sciences to build single dimension estimates of socioeconomic status. In this post I will first walk through the intuition and math behind PCA, and then provide a simple example of its use in R to generate a simple asset index.
IntuitionDimension reduction is any process by which we reduce the number of variables in a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is an improper prior?</title>
      <link>/post/2020/03/16/what-is-an-improper-prior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/03/16/what-is-an-improper-prior/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionSince I’ve purchased improperprior.com it seems prudent that I write a short post explaining improper priors.
Typical Bayesian ProcessIn Bayesian statistics we exploit Bayes’ theorem to learn something about a population parameter. For example, if we have data \(Y\) that follow a Binomial distribution, and we would like to estimate the \(\theta\) parameter, we would compute:
\[P(\theta|Y) = \frac{L(Y|\theta)P(\theta)}{P(Y)}.\]
In this case:
\(P(\theta|Y)\) is the posterior probability, this is what we’d like to estimate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous and Binary Dependent Variables</title>
      <link>/post/2020/02/14/continuous-and-binary-dependent-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/02/14/continuous-and-binary-dependent-variables/</guid>
      <description>R Setup# Data manipulationlibrary(dplyr)library(purrr)library(tidyr)# Modelinglibrary(broom)# Plotting and tableslibrary(ggplot2)library(patchwork)library(ggthemes)library(knitr)# R settingstheme_set(theme_tufte() + theme(legend.position = &amp;quot;none&amp;quot;))opts_chunk$set(echo = T, warning = F, message = F, tidy = F,fig.width = 8.5, fig.height = 6)IntroductionIn his 2011 paper “Land tenure and investment incentives: Evidence from West Africa,” James Fenske notes that “studies that use binary investment measures…are also less likely to find a statistically significant effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Language for Survey Programming</title>
      <link>/post/2020/01/05/a-language-for-survey-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/01/05/a-language-for-survey-programming/</guid>
      <description>What’s wrong with XLSForms?XLSForm defines a very accessible (other than reliance on Excel) standard for programming surveys compatible with OpenDataKit, SurveyCTO, and a myriad of other data collection tools used in low/no connectivity environments. XLSForm’s are dead easy to program, but can produce very complex surveys. However, in my ~5 years of programming XLSForm surveys I’ve encountered a few problems caused by the reliance on Excel for programming:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Data Science</title>
      <link>/bad-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bad-data-science/</guid>
      <description>There’s a lot of bad data science out there.
FightCOVID19: To me this looks like a blatant attempt to profit (at least reputationally) from the COVID-19 pandemic. At the time I am writing this, it looks like the author of this repo has felt the need to build a massive ecosystem (Android/iOS/Web apps? Whos is this for?) around a pre-trained Neural Net, updated with COVID-19 victim chest scans. While updating pre-trained models is standard (and very often a good idea!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Interview Questions</title>
      <link>/data-science-interview-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-science-interview-questions/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionI’ve seen a number of articles/posts pop up around the internet with lists of data science interview questions. I thought it might be a good exercise in communication and data science knowledge to answer these questions. I am finding it harder than I would have expected to write good (and hopefully useful) answers!
Question sources:
HackerNoon - 160+ Data Science Interview QuestionsAdditional resources:
Alexey Grigorev has put together a whole GitHub repo with data science interview questions and answers, available here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>