<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>r on Ben Ewing | Improper Prior</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in r on Ben Ewing | Improper Prior</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning SQL</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/23/learning-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/23/learning-sql/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been using the past few weeks to improve my SQL fluency, and I just wanted to share a few quick resources that I’ve found useful.
SQLZoo. The quizzes and questions hit the perfect balance of challenging but not so hard that it breaks my sense of flow.
The sqlite3 package for Python and RSQLite package for R. While one certainly could install and use something like PostgreSQL on their laptop (and it’s definitely a useful tool to learn!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Principal Component Analysis to Estimate Socioeconomic Status</title>
      <link>/post/2020/03/21/using-principal-component-analysis-to-estimate-socioeconomic-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/03/21/using-principal-component-analysis-to-estimate-socioeconomic-status/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionPrincipal Component Analysis (PCA) is a dimension reduction technique that is commonly used in the social sciences to build single dimension estimates of socioeconomic status. In this post I will first walk through the intuition and math behind PCA, and then provide a simple example of its use in R to generate a simple asset index.
IntuitionDimension reduction is any process by which we reduce the number of variables in a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous and Binary Dependent Variables</title>
      <link>/post/2020/02/14/continuous-and-binary-dependent-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/02/14/continuous-and-binary-dependent-variables/</guid>
      <description>R Setup# Data manipulationlibrary(dplyr)library(purrr)library(tidyr)# Modelinglibrary(broom)# Plotting and tableslibrary(ggplot2)library(patchwork)library(ggthemes)library(knitr)# R settingstheme_set(theme_tufte() + theme(legend.position = &amp;quot;none&amp;quot;))opts_chunk$set(echo = T, warning = F, message = F, tidy = F,fig.width = 8.5, fig.height = 6)IntroductionIn his 2011 paper “Land tenure and investment incentives: Evidence from West Africa,” James Fenske notes that “studies that use binary investment measures…are also less likely to find a statistically significant effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Language for Survey Programming</title>
      <link>/post/2020/01/05/a-language-for-survey-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/01/05/a-language-for-survey-programming/</guid>
      <description>What’s wrong with XLSForms?XLSForm defines a very accessible (other than reliance on Excel) standard for programming surveys compatible with OpenDataKit, SurveyCTO, and a myriad of other data collection tools used in low/no connectivity environments. XLSForm’s are dead easy to program, but can produce very complex surveys. However, in my ~5 years of programming XLSForm surveys I’ve encountered a few problems caused by the reliance on Excel for programming:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>